# Nho Nguyen Hoai

HCMC, VN nhoxtvt@gmail.com (84) 912 521 560

#### **SUMMARY**

As a software developer, I've always valued building scalable, well-documented code. I prefer to collaborate, but I can also manage projects on my own. I've been a software developer for over 4+ years and have worked on over 12+ projects. Throughout the project, I typically worked on the FE, BE, and Mobile Dev positions concurrently. Aside from the abilities listed above, I've also worked with Heroku, Vercel, Netlify, AWS and Google Service. I am eager to learn new technologies in order to increase the quality of my work, and I am always eager to learn and work in a software engineering organization.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Full Stack Developer**

NUS Technology • HCMC

12/2022 - Present

- I worked on over 10 projects with many kinds of products, such as: E-commerce, Traveling, Construction, Education, Content Management Systems, Security, Logistics, ...
- I replaced three previous young developers and compensated for their poor performance with higher code quality, resulting in a 60% reduction in development costs and time.
- I found a strategy to improve the interface while delivering rapid and high-quality photographs to customers, double the previous version's access speed.
- Integrating the Stripe payment mechanism inside the application, making it easier for users to pay, self-discuss with clients, and plan to execute complicated payment cycles.
- Changed old upload technique into high-performance upload with background task and real-time picture processing, assisting customer in bringing over three contracts with my proposal.
- I built the application using an open platform that changes building sites in two languages at the same time: Golang and NodeJS, and I built my own Oauth2 authentication with Golang and Authlete. I can handle many tasks at once and assist teammates in addressing difficult problems in Oauth2 builds. (https://www.landlog.info/en/)
- Self-configuring docker information for optimal time preparation step for the project's newcomers and synchonized develop environment, as well as building a CI/CD system for the project on Github, assists in more efficiently analyzing code quality. By supporting teammates in analyzing code quality and finding the best approach to enhance it, you can save 60% of your time.

# Technical Leader & Full Stack Developer

GPT Group • HCMC

05/2021 - 11/2021

- Worked on over 2 projects, throughout the project, I reviewed and improved quality code for team members
- · Help team refactor and create reusable components and save over 200 hours of development time per month
- Create and construct a complex task management, appointment reminder, and action automation system. Customers were awarded three contracts, and earnings increased by \$300,000 over the prior year.
- Take ownership of the project, ensure the quality of the code base and control technical debts
- Provide architectural and design direction, evaluate the risk and the impact of features and implementations on the system
- · Determine the sprint goal and task list for each sprint and estimate each task along with team members

## **Full Stack Developer**

Freelancer • HCMC 02/2019 - 04/2021

• I worked as a Full Stack mobile developer. I helped the team edit the design version and build a couple complicated UIs with complicated animations. I also built a system and handled data from a crawler system, data filtering, and real-time handler for it.

- I front-end developed UI for a constructor project using SPA and the language ReactJS. I completed tasks ahead of estimation and improved the point of SEO for the project.
- Build a recruitment project with a number of standard features, like: the ability to handle PDF and image files from simple data, the ability to generate form input in real time to a canvas and parse it into a product like a logo, banner, or resume (.pdf), and the ability to re-upload files that have been generated and process edits in this one.

#### **SKILL**

#### **Cloud Services**

- · Google Cloud Service
- · Amazon Web Service

## **Program Languages**

- Javascript (ES6, NodeJS)
- Typescript
- Frontend development: HTML/CSS/SCSS

#### Frameworks

- NextIS
- · ReactJS
- ReactNative
- VueJS (Vue 2 and Vue 3)
- NestJS
- ExpressJS
- · AdonisJS

## CI/CD

- · Bitbucket pipeline
- · Github pipeline
- AWS pipeline
- · Docker and docker compose

#### **Databases**

- PostgreSQL
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Firestore
- Redis

## **Deployment**

- · Google Cloud Service
- · Amazon Web Service
- Heroku
- Vercel
- · Netlify

#### Others

- In-depth git knowledge
- · Agile / Scrum
- · Artificial intelligence: OpenAI API
- · RESTful APIs
- Mail services: Sendgrid, Brevo, Elastic
- SMS service: TwilioPayment: Stripe

- Authentication: Authlete, Oauth2
- · Serverless: Google Cloud Function
- · Realtime processing: SocketIO, WebSocket
- Familiar with the popular libraries for Front end, such as: Bootstrap, Tailwind, AntDesign, Quasar, VueX, Redux, Material UI, ChakraUI, AntDesign, etc.
- Familiar with quality testing like JestJS, etc.
- Expert in responsive, mobile first development and mindset
- Intermediate English (Good reading/writing skills, basic verbal communication)

## **EDUCATION**

# **Software Engineering**

HUTECH University • HCMC 08/2022

• Graduated summa cum laude - 3.43 + GPA

## **AWARDS**

Top 10 IT Got Talent (HUTECH), Top 3 Innovative software (HUTECH)